Inventory of the Selig J. Seligman papers, 1942-1968
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Selig J. Seligman papers
1942-1968
Seligman, Selig J.
03405
3.27 cubic ft. (6 boxes) + 633 MB
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The collection contains materials relating to the Hollywood production career of Selig J. Seligman.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection has been minimally processed.
Biography of Selig J. Seligman
Seligman (1918-1969) was a lawyer turned television and motion picture producer. During the 1950s Seligman served as a vice president of the American Broadcasting Company and the General Manager of KABC-TV in Los Angeles, California. In 1961 he founded the production company Selmur Productions. He was perhaps best known for producing the television series “Combat!” and the movie “Charly.”
Scope and Content
The Selig J. Seligman papers contain materials relating to the Hollywood producing career of Selig J. Seligman. The bulk of the collection consists of scripts and production files for television shows and movies that Seligman produced. The majority of these files are from Seligman’s production company, Selmur Productions. Other materials include an audio recording of an interview with Seligman, correspondence, books, newspaper clippings, and testimony to the FCC. Some of the productions covered by the collection include “Charly,” “Alexander the Great,” and “Combat!”
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Selig J. Seligman at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Selig J. Seligman in 1970 and Lucy Seligman from 2010-2016.
Access Terms
Motion pictures--Production and direction--United States.; Television--Production and direction--United States.; Television programs--United States.; Motion picture producers and directors.; Television producers and directors.;; Scripts.;; Selmur Productions.; Combat! (Television program); Charly (Motion picture)
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Performing Arts; Social Life and Customs; People, Ethnicity, and Culture
Container List
- Series I. Scripts and Treatments
  - Candy, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charly, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Day in Court, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diamonds for Breakfast, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Don't Touch the Water, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The High Commissioner, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Inquest, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Last Choctaw" by H.H. Madsen, undated (Box 6)
  - Midas Run, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Pinkertons, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Searcher, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Smashing Time, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stiletto, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Stranger in the House" from the novel by Georges Simenon, August 24, 1966 (Box 6)
  - World in a Jug, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II. Production and Information Files
  - Accused - Photograph, Judge Edgar Allen Jones, Jr., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Alexander the Great, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folders 5-7)
  - Alexander the Great - Set Sketch, circa 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Charly, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folders 1-2)
  - Charly - Phonograph Record, Music from Charly, circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Charly - Photographs, Charly Creators with Press, circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Combat!, 1962-1963 (Box 3 and 6)
  - Combat! - Photograph for TV Guide Cover, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Combat! - Photographs and Plaque, Department of Army Award, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Discovery, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stranger in the House, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Script Notes, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Movie or TV Producion, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series III. Miscellaneous Professional Files
  - Adresses by Seligman and KABC-TV News Releases, 1957-1965 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Biographical File - O'Brian, John Lord, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Biographical File - Seligman, Selig J., 1942, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Biographical File - Shatner, William, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Book - The Big Deal (Honey on the Hill) by Seligman, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Book - Garrison's Gorillas by Jack Pearl (Based on Seligman Production), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1968 (Box 4 and 6)
  - Illustrations for Seligman Talk, by John Dunn, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Interview (audio) - Seligman and Ralph Nelson, conducted by Ernest Taub (CD-R), 1967 (Digital, Folder ahcdm_03405_001)
  - News Clippings, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folders 9-10)
  - Photographs - Barkley, Alben William, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs - Seligman, Selig J., circa 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - Weeki Wachee, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Photographs - unidentified, undated (Box 6)
  - Publicity Posters Scrapbook (Cop-Out, The Rover, A Minute to Pray, a Second to Die, Charly, The High Commissioner, and Candy, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Statement by Seligman to FCC for the Study of Radio and Television Network Broadcasters, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)